# **Monica Tan**

# **User Experience Designer**

#### **SUMMARY**

User experience designer specializing in ideation and interaction design for desktop, web, and mobile applications. Has worked on user experience projects with the leading technology companies including; Cisco, Citrix, Intuit, Hewlett-Packard, Well Fargo, and Apple.

#### **PROFESSIONAL SKILLS**

- Excellent understanding of user interface design principles, product build cycle and working within a cross-functional team under tight deadlines.
- Solid understanding of requirements gathering process and product visioning, including facilitation of brainstorming and ideation sessions.
- Experience with all phases of user experience design; including user profile / persona development, user scenario documentation, task analysis, card sorting, usability test moderation, and reporting.
- Champion the best user experience process to deliver a solution that exceeds client expectations.
- Manage and mentor up to eight User Experience Designers, including contractors and full-time employees.
- Participation in agile scrum teams, with training in agile development processes.
- Ability to understand and strategize solutions based on web analytics. Working knowledge of *Omniture Site Catalyst and Google Analytics*.
- Expert at creating functional specifications including wireframes, mockups and interaction specifications using: Adobe PhotoShop, Illustrator, Fireworks, Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint), Visio, and Axure.
- Ability to create click-able prototypes using HTML (Dreamweaver & FrontPage), Axure, and InVision.
- Working knowledge of web programming with supporting coursework: HTML, DHTML, JavaScript, CSS, Flash, and AJAX.
- Excellent written, verbal and personal communication skills.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

2013 – 2016 AlienVault

### **Director of User Experience**

Hired as sole user interface designer for a 70-person startup. Redesigned and am currently architecting the flagship product AlienVault USM. Mentor junior visual designer.

2011 - 2012 ShopWell

# **User Experience Lead**

Hired as sole user interface designer for an 8-person start-up. Worked on launching the 2.0 redesign of existing mobile iPhone app. Continued enhancements on website until acquisition by HarvestMark.

Design simple and intuitive user interfaces on connected devices, utilizing new technologies.

#### CONTACT

theemptydesign@gmail.com

Twitter: theemptydesign Mobile: 650.823.9831

References available upon request.

#### **COMPETENCIES**

- Requirements Gathering/ Product Vision
- User Research / Usability Testing
- Concepting / Brainstorming / Personas
- User Scenarios
- User Flows / Page Flows/ Swim Lanes
- Card Sorting
- Sitemaps / Blueprints
- Wireframes
- Specifications
- Prototyping
- Project Management
- iPhone App Design

# KNOWLEDGEABLE

Wordpress, Google Analytics, Omniture (Adobe Marketing Cloud), Mobile App design, iPad design, and ecommerce design.

**EDUCATION** 

2008 – 2011 LEVEL Studios

#### **User Experience Manager**

Manage and mentor up to eight user experience designers, both senior and junior. Built user experience practice to include product visioning, ideation, user needs gathering, and prototyping.

## **Information Architect**

Deliver on time and on budget while delighting customers with amazing solutions. Promoted to User Experience Manager after a year as Senior User Information Architect.

# 2004 - 2008 (Start-up Phase)

# **Senior User Interface Designer**

StarCite, Inc

Hired and managed an external agency to aid in a large visual redesign of multiple products. Delivered a new look that was very well received by customers.

# **User Interface Designer**

Visible Path - Hoover's

Hired as sole user interface designer for a 20-person start-up. Worked on enhancements, which aided in the purchase by Hoover's in 2008.

#### **Senior User Interface Designer**

PhotoSite - United Online

Used Omniture Site Catalyst (Adobe Marketing Cloud) to discover areas of improvement within the online photo-sharing experience. Industry knowledge in photo-sharing and social networking.

#### **Senior User Interface Designer**

WildCard Systems – eFunds

Created solutions for complex problems using existing technologies. Group patent pending for gift card ordering process using Excel.

2003-2004 Citrix Systems, Inc

# **Senior User Interface Designer**

Re-architected and redesigned the Citrix Password Manager user interface for IT administrators.

2000 – 2003 Intuit, Corp

### **User Interface Designer**

Worked on first Web release of Intuit Payroll. Introduced remote usability testing methodologies. Conducted primary research to create user personas.

# 1998 – 2000 Digital Equipment - Compaq Computers

#### **Human Factors Engineer**

Conducted and analyzed usability study for large fast food chain kiosk training system. Mentored by Dennis Wixon on contextual inquiry practices.

1994 – 1998 Bachelors of Science University of Massachusetts

at Amherst Major: Biology Minor: Psychology Concentration: Technical

Writing